Cortlandt Winters

cort@cortwinters.net (518) 944-5676

Profile:

Client Side Architect

Senior Javascript professional with two decades experience crafting responsive and tactile client side experiences in Dynamic Html, Flash, Flex, Html5 and native platforms for both desktops and small devices. Increasing amounts of server side experience as well. Excellent written and verbal communication skills, object oriented and functional programming skills, user interface and graphic design skills, interactive graphics, data visualization and programmatic animation. A pleasant person to work with high standards and who loves to both mentor and learn from others.

Languages: Javascript(3, 4, 5, Es6), Python, C, C++, ML, Groovy Some C#, Java, Ruby and Elixir Specs and Standards: TCP/IP, HTTP, RTMP, XMPP, REST, XML, XSLT, HTML, SVG and CSS

Frameworks: Backbone, React, Vue + others on the client side, Grails, Django and Hapi server side.

Databases: SQLLite, MongoDb, LINQ and SQL Server, Some Postgres

Experience:

NYSED: Jan 2016 - present

Instructional Technologist II- Maintain and upgrade an internal content management system written with Java and Spring Boot server side and Vuejs client side.

Troy Web Consulting: Feb 2013 - Oct 2015

Senior Client Side Architect- Translate legacy applications from Flex to Html5 with Backbone, JQuery, Javascript and Raphael. Re-architect a .Net Webforms application for better perfomance and usability using C#, JQuery, javascript and css.

Independent Contractor: May 2012 - Feb 2013

Mobile Designer and Game Programmer- Designed mobile interfaces and web based games using Knockoutjs and Html5 and a native game processing tool with Flex and sqlite.

Aurora Studios : Mar-Apr 2012

Mobile Phone Developer- Programmed a mobile application for IOS and Android devices using the Flex mobile framework and Actionscript 3. The application is a study tool to teach medical terminology to college students and is freely downloadable on both Itunes and the Amazon App store as "Med Term Mastery"

Troy Web Consulting: Jan 2006- Mar 2012

Senior Technologist- Designed and developed HTML, Flex and Laszlo user interfaces for numerous clients including Kineticast, Barclays, Surewest, Prentice Hall, Own America, Idea Champions, Laszlo Systems, NYS Dept of Environmental Conservation, NYS Attorney Generals office and others. Specialized in component development, data visualization, dynamic PDF programming, dynamic skinning and theming, interactive video and utilizing flash media server.

Rennselaer Polytechnic Institute: July 2004 - Jan 2006

Research Programmer- Designed and programed math teaching tools for k-12 curriculum with Flash and Actionscript. Also debugged existing tools and converted existing Java Applets to Actionscript

Independent Contractor: Jan 2002 - June 2004

Actionscript Programmer - Performed contract work for Macromedia, Laszlo Systems and other companies utilizing Flash, Laszlo, Macromedia Communication Server, and Macromedia Central. For Macromedia wrote an internal prototype that combined video capture in a browser with blogging and instant messaging. Developed components and worked on sample applications for Macromedia Central, the first version of what is now the Adobe Air runtime. Work for other companies included programming with Actionscript and illustration work. For Laszlo Systems, created a rich text editor component that was used in Laszlo Mail, an early competitor of Gmail.

General Dynamics Defense Systems - Techsite: Mar 2000 - Nov 2001

Senior Software Design Engineer - Led the development of a complex DHTML test application for k-12, math, science and literature content. Created a DTD and XSLT publishing tool to read and validate data, execute tests and talk to Java Servlets. Designed and developed interactive components in Flash4 for embedding in the DHTML engine. Upon the release of Flash5, led in the effort to convert the DHTML test engine into a Flash only test engine. Trained a group of other developers and led in the development of a number of additional components including a calculator, graphing calculator, line, protractor, ruler, compass, periodic table and writing tools.

SUNY Research Foundation: Jan 1995 - Mar 2000

Senior Programmer/Analyst - Led in all aspects of the design, development, deployment and support of high-end multimedia training CD programs. Tasks included; graphic design, user interface design, modularization of design, storyboards, programming in Openscript, Visual C++ and Actionscript, programming of MPEG video functionality via the Microsoft MCI API, usability testing, content creation, content editing, graphic, audio and video media creation, media editing, CD packaging and setup. Helped develop statewide standards for usability and distribution. Developed online training resources for a state agency intranet.

National Center on Literature Teaching and Learning: Jan 1994 - Jan 1995

Educational Software Developer - Designed and implemented windows software for teaching English as a second language to adults in C++, Prolog and Toolbook. Designed software for teaching literature understanding to children. Implemented a windows paint program for children in C++. Designed, implemented and distributed a database of teacher's reviews of commercial software. Designed and implemented a multimedia CD based on Robert Frost poetry. Designed tools for online collaboration

Bart Sears - DC Comics / Jewel Advertising: June 1989 - Nov 1990

Comic Book Artist / Illustrator - Subcontracted to pencil the backgrounds for six issues of 'Justice League Europe', the sixth best selling comic book in the nation at the time and produced illustrations for nationwide advertising campaigns.

Education:

MS in Computer Science, SUNY at Albany 1997

BA in Filmmaking and Dramatic Literature, Vassar College 1989